《盲点》前情回顾
Previously on "Blindspot"...
我觉得无名氏就是泰勒·肖
I think Jane Doe is Taylor Shaw.
泰勒·肖都失踪25年了
Taylor Shaw has been missing for 25 years.
是的  现在她回来了
Yeah, and she's not missing anymore.
我们化验了你的DNA
We had your DNA tested
跟泰勒的对比  看是否一样
to see if it matched Taylor's.
你有结果了吗
You have the results?
你就是泰勒·肖
You are Taylor Shaw.
你25年来一直相信爸爸犯了谋杀罪
You spent 25 years convinced dad committed a murder
可他从没做过
that never even happened.
她还活着  柯特
She's alive, Kurt.
那你为什么要隐瞒你去了哪儿
Then why did you lie? About where you were?
你为什么...
Why did you...
因为我当时想自杀
Because I was trying to kill myself!
停止调查汤姆·卡特失踪一事
Stop looking into Tom Carter's disappearance,
否则你爱的人会一个个被杀
or people you love will start to die.
我不能继续下去了
I can't do this anymore.
-什么  -我对你没有那种感情
- What? - I don't feel the same way.
-我知道你爱我  -不  我不爱
- I know that you love me. - No, I don't.
要是我没发现呢
What if I didn't notice?
我知道你会发现的
I knew you would.
我们...错过了
our timing is... is just off.
我浪费了那么多精力  研究为什么行不通
I wasted so much energy on why it wouldn't work.
我爱他
I loved him.
如今他不在了
And now he's gone.
你一直都表现出
You always act like everything's going
一切尽在计划之中的样子
completely according to plan.
一切回到正轨
Things are back on track.
现在怎么办
So what now?
这是什么破歌
你知道我们在后面能听见这破歌吧
说真的  老兄  把它关上
怎么回事
有埋伏
是伏击
那是什么东西
快趴下
莎拉
Sarah?
索亚的书
索亚
Sawyer?
莎拉
Sarah?
我们和珍妮在一起  我周五来取剩下的东西
莎拉
莎拉  是我
Sarah, it's me.
出什么事了
What's going on?
收到留言给我回电话
Give me a call when you get this.
你好
Hello?
这里是巴卡斯餐厅来电确认
This is Bacchus confirming
您预订了今晚八点的两人桌
your reservation tonight at 8:00 P.M. for two people.
抱歉  我...  我没预订过今晚的位子
Sorry, I-- I don't have a reservation for tonight.
是用大卫·瓦格纳的名字预订的
Booked under David Wagner?
他特别要求拨打这个号码
He gave very specific instructions to call this number.
他是什么时候...
Wh-When did he...
他上个月预订的
He made the reservation last month.
抱歉  我...  我要挂了
Sorry, I-- I have to go.
好了
All right.
换我
Step in.
你今天跟莎拉谈过了吗
You talk to Sarah today?
没有
Nope.
她要搬出去了
She's moving out.
你知道原因吗
Any idea why?
你们出什么问题了吗
Something going on with you guys?
是因为...
It's...
我们分手了
we broke up.
什么时候
When?
昨晚
Last night.
发生什么事了
What happened?
发生什么并不重要
Doesn't matter what happened.
反正我们是分手了
We're not dating anymore.
你该开心了
You should be happy.
我并不开心  因为她不开心
I'm not happy 'cause she's not happy.
接着来
Come on.
我打不过你的
I really can't win with you, man.
我真的做不到
I really can't.
早啊  简
Mornin', Jane.
早
Oh, hey, mornin'.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
什么
What?
今天是你...  是泰勒的生日
It's yours-- Taylor's, birthday, today.
我...  我甚至都不...
Oh, I... I didn't even...
给
Here.
我给你准备了礼物
I got you something.
我正要找你呢
Just the person I was looking for.
早啊
Morning.
-你好  简  -艾莉
- Hey, Jane. - Allie.
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
去楼上开人事管理办公室的通报会
OPM briefing upstairs,
我想可以顺路来看看
so I thought I'd stop in on my way.
如果你们现在有事
I can come back later
我可以过会再来
if you guys are in the middle of something.
不  不必  我得走了
No, no, no, no, I have to go.
真是个惊喜
This is a nice surprise.
我给你带了早餐
I brought you breakfast.
罂粟籽松饼和可塔朵咖啡  你最爱的口味
Poppy seed muffin and Cortado, just the way you like it.
最好不过
It better be.
你今晚还会来吗
Are you coming over again tonight?
-好啊  -我正想好好展示一下厨艺
- Yes. - I was thinking about being ambitious and cooking.
真的吗
Really?
在上次之后还要下厨吗
After last time?
失火可不全是我的错
That fire was not entirely my fault.
是某人让我有点分心
Someone got me a little distracted.
可不是  你要拿烤箱加热
Yeah! You were trying to heat up a pizza
盒装披萨啊
inside the box inside an oven.
好吧  也许应该由你负责准备吃的
Okay, maybe you should be in charge of the food.
好
Good.
交给我吧
I'll do that.
好吧  那八点钟见
All right, so, um, see you at eight?
好
Okay.
回头见
Bye.
再见
早上好  你来的真及时
Morning, you're just in time.
有什么发现吗
What do we got?
一辆运钞车遭劫
Uh, an armored truck was robbed.
还有呢
And?
没错  运钞车
Yes, um, the truck.
案件发生在今早
It happened this morning
地点在罗克兰  或者...
in Rockland, or...
-不  没在那里  -威彻斯特郡
- No, that's not it.-  Westchester County.
案发地在威彻斯特郡
It was Westchester County.
跟纹身有关联吗
Tattoo connections?
是的  没错  绝对有关
Yes, yes, definitely connected.
肯定是这样
That is an affirmative, um...
这些是州警用手机拍摄的图片
These are cell phone photos from the state troopers.
他们说那辆运钞车
They said that the truck
遭到了全副武装的歹徒们的伏击
was ambushed by heavily armed gunmen.
司机和一名守卫都遇害了
The driver and a guard were killed.
这个案子跟哪块纹身相关
Which tattoo is this connected to?
这个正方形加菱形的设计
So this... square and diamond design
跟运钞车的标志完全吻合
is an exact match with the truck logo.
R.O.R.安保
虽然不知道这代表什么
And I couldn't figure it out,
但是它的对称性让我想到了镜像
but the symmetry of it made me think of mirror images,
镜像能够形成几何图形
which led to geometric shapes...
我们能回到劫案上来吗
Can we get back to the robbery?
稍等  我想听听她是如何推演的
Hold on a second, I want to hear how she cracked it.
或许能帮助了解案情
It might inform the case.
好吧  这其实没有什么指向性
Well, it didn't really lead anywhere,
但背后肯定是有原因的
but that's for a reason.
这个标志是为了一个
So this logo was created
不存在的公司设计的
for a company that doesn't exist.
不存在是什么意思
What do you mean it doesn't exist?
因为R.O.R.安保公司没有在
R.O.R. Security isn't registered
运输部或任何地方注册登记过
with the DOT or anywhere, for that matter.
但如果这辆运钞车没有登记过
But if the truck wasn't registered,
我们就没办法查清楚他们运送的是什么东西
we have no way of knowing what they were transporting.
显然那件东西重要到
Clearly something valuable enough
需要运钞车护送
you need an armored truck.
甚至有人不惜开杀戒
And worth killing for.
问题是
Question is,
车里装的到底是什么
is what was inside that truck?
第二组轮胎印迹
Second set of tire marks.
从尺寸推断是一辆越野车
SUVs, judging from their size.
它们围堵了运钞车  把它逼停到路边
They converged on the truck, ran it off the road.
门是被融开的
These doors were melted open.
工具是割炬或者喷枪
A torch or a thermal lance.
看不出他们在运送什么
No signs of what they were moving.
守卫试图逃跑的时候在这里中枪了
Guard got shot here trying to escape.
他几乎没有逃生的可能
He didn't stand much of a chance.
这些家伙用的是穿甲弹
These guys used armor-piercing bullets.
司机甚至还没来及逃出运钞车
The driver didn't even make it out of the truck
就被穿透玻璃的子弹击中了
before he was shot through the window.
打扰一下  你们得过来看看这个
Excuse me. Got something you need to see.
看来运钞车里是有三个人的
So there were three guys in the truck.
检查一下
Check that out.
"阿托品及氯解磷定
"Atropine and pralidoxime.
可用于神经性毒剂"
for use in nerve agent poisoning."
这是沙林毒气的解毒剂
It's the antidote for sarin gas.
看来他们运送的是化学武器
So they were transporting chemical weapons.
盲   点
第一季  第十六集
帕特森  知道沙林毒气有可能是哪来的吗
Patterson... any idea where the sarin came from?
美国化工局距离这里约24公里
The USA CMA is located just 15 miles away.
我不信这是巧合
Doubt that's a coincidence.
什么局
What is that?
美国陆军化工原料局
The United States Army Chemical Materials Agency.
我们所有的化学武器都由他们保管或销毁
They store and destroy all of our chemical weapons.
谁是那里的负责人
Who's in charge there?
马克·谢里登将军
General Mark Sheridan.
梅菲尔正在联系他的办公室
Mayfair's reaching out to his office right now.
你有受害者的信息吗
You got anything on the victims?
李佑贞  朴永  赵珉海
Yoo Jin Lee, Young Park, and Min Ha Cho.
都是韩国人  没有犯罪前科
All South Korean Nationals, clean criminal records.
他们在陆化局工作吗
Did they work at the CMA?
不是
No.
那他们从哪儿弄到的沙林毒气
So where did they get sarin from?
还不知道
I don't know yet.
我正在扩建一份国内外
I'm building out the Koreans'
已知的韩国工作者名单
known associates here and abroad.
他们是如何抵达美国的
How'd they get in the country?
全部通过正当途径
It was all above board.
他们都持有位于布鲁克林的
They had work visas sponsored by the president
进出口公司的董事长颁发的工作签证
of an import/export company based in Brooklyn.
瓦妮莎·张
Vanessa Chang.
把她带来  我们马上回去
Bring her in. We're on our way back now.
深深的怀念  泰勒·肖
泰勒今天本将满三十岁
Taylor would have been 30 today.
我没有一天不在想念她
Not a day goes by that I don't think of her.
想象她本该长成一位美丽的女子
Imagine the beautiful woman she would have become.
简  简
Jane. Jane!
走吗
You coming?
怎么会发生这种事
How could this happen?
如果他们真有沙林毒气
If they're in possession of sarin gas,
肯定不是从我们这里流出去的
it didn't come from our facility.
唯一会移动那些容器罐的时刻
The only time those canisters are moved
就是它们被送去焚毁的时候
is when they're taken to be incinerated.
即便如此  为了防止有人擅动和盗窃
Even then, we've got a strict multi-level security protocol
我们制定了一份严密的多层级安全协议
in place to prevent tampering and theft.
我的天啊  发生了什么
Oh, my God. What happened?
现在还在展开调查
It's still an open investigation,
所以我们不能随意地谈论案件细节
so we're not at liberty to discuss details.
你很了解他们吗
Did you... know them well?
我以为是的
I thought I did.
三年前我给他们提供了工作签证
I sponsored their work visas three years ago.
我把他们留在公司当司机
I gave them jobs as drivers with my company.
所以凶手可能就是你们的员工
So it could have been one of your employees.
我严重怀疑
I seriously doubt it.
我们将会审问过去两年内
We're gonna have to question everyone who had access
每一个能够接触沙林毒气的人
to the sarin in the last two years.
当然
Of course.
一个月前  我发现朴永
A month ago, I found out that Young
从我的库房里偷取古玩  转手卖掉
was stealing antiques from my warehouse and reselling them.
我开始仔细调查  却发现
I tried to get to the bottom of it and discovered
佑贞和珉海也牵涉其中
that Jin and Min Ha were also involved.
你给他们作担保之前
You must have done background checks
一定做过背景调查  有哪里不对劲吗
before you sponsored them-- any red flags come up?
当时没发现  但后来我打听到
Nothing at the time, but I started asking around
佑贞和一个韩国黑帮
and I heard a rumor that Yoo Jin had ties
似乎有牵连
to a Korean gang.
沙林毒气有多可怕
How bad is sarin?
简单来说  会使人窒息同时溶解人体器官
To be blunt, it melts your organs while you asphyxiate.
好像美国国税局正在找你麻烦吧
Looks like you've been having some trouble with the IRS.
如果你是在暗示说我参与了
If you're insinuating that I'm involved
什么非法活动...
in some illegal activity...
我们没有在暗示什么
We're not insinuating anything.
只是想查明整件事
Just trying to get the full story.
我父亲刚到美国时身上只有两百美金
My father came to this country with $200 in his pocket.
他夜以继日地工作
He worked day and night
让我们几个孩子能过上好日子
to build a life for me and my brothers.
钱会让人做出疯狂的事
Money makes people do crazy things,
尤其是在走投无路的时候
especially when their back's against the wall.
我绝不会做有辱自己
I would never do anything to jeopardize
或家族的名誉的事
my reputation or my family.
如果那些人有一卡车的沙林毒气
If those guys have a truckload of it,
就足以毁灭整个国家
could wipe out the whole state.
有什么进展
What's the update?
我查到些东西
I think I got something.
这三个韩国人在抢劫前二十分钟
All three of the Koreans turned off their phones
同时关掉了他们的手机
at the same time, about 20 minutes before the robbery.
可能是为了转移沙林毒气时不被追踪
Probably so they couldn't be detected transporting the sarin.
我通过交叉比对发现一个已知关联人
My vector search found a known associate
也在上述同一时刻关掉了手机
who turned off his cell phone at the exact same time.
萨姆·李  在昆斯出生长大
Sam Lee, born and raised in Queens.
现在看起来像是个四人团伙
Now it's starting to look like a four-man crew.
但只有三具尸体
Except there's no fourth body.
他可能是另一个团伙的
He could have been working for the other team.
你真觉得他和那些劫匪是一伙的吗
Do you really think he was actually on side with the robbers?
他可能是内线
He might be their inside man.
有道理
Makes sense...
这样劫匪就知道该在何时何地袭击
the heist team would know when and where to strike.
司机被近距离射杀  对吧
The driver was shot at close range, wasn't he?
对  子弹穿过车窗
Yeah, through the passenger window.
也可能是从驾驶室内射出
Or, from inside the cab.
我们得马上找到萨姆·李
We need to find this Sam Lee now.
好的  他手机关机了
Okay, his cell phone's turned off,
但我在诺克斯维尔查到一个地址
but I have an address in K-town.
-好  -等等
- Okay. - Hang on!
沙林毒气解药
Sarin gas antidotes.
但愿用不上  不过假如你们吸入毒气
God forbid you need them, but if you get exposed,
就赶紧给自己注射
you inject yourself immediately.
否则体内器官一分钟内就会衰竭
Internal organ failure happens within a minute.
很惨的
It's not pretty.
-好了  行动吧  -谢谢你
- Okay. Let's move. - Thank you.
157号  五单元
1-5-7, unit 5.
五楼
Fifth floor.
又是没电梯的公寓
Always got to be a walk-up.
他在那  那就是萨姆
There he is. That's Sam.
这里不行  我的位置无法瞄准
It's no good for me, I got no shot!
我也是
Me, either!
上  他倒地了  快上
Go! Down, down, down! Go!
人质安全
Hostage clear!
纽约警局马上到
NYPD is on the way.
干得漂亮
Nice shot.
萨姆·李
Sam Lee.
像是张出入权限卡
Looks like some kind of security access card.
我不认为他这栋楼里有车库
I don't think his building has a garage.
可能是他们藏毒气罐的地方
It might be where they're keeping the canisters.
同一个号码十二个未接来电
12 missed calls from the same number.
看看是谁这么着急联系他
Let's see who's so desperate to talk.
拨号中
萨姆
Sam?
你为什么不接电话
Why haven't you picked up your phone?
萨姆
Sam?
是将军
The General.
今天本该是
Today would've been
我和大卫的一周年纪念日
my one-year anniversary with David.
我一直努力不去想这事
And I've been trying to block it out,
直到今天早上  我俩最喜欢的餐厅打来电话
until I got a call from our favorite restaurant this morning...
确认今晚的餐桌预定
confirming a table for tonight.
一定是大卫预定的
So David must have booked it.
我明白
I see.
除此之外  今天《时代周刊》上
And on top of that, the "Times" published
登了他写的最后一份填字游戏
his last crossword puzzle today,
所以我觉得自己在不断收到他的讯息
so I feel like I keep getting these messages from him,
我知道这听起来...
and I know it sounds--
我觉得你应该去
I think you should go.
什么
What?
今晚那家餐厅
To the dinner.
我觉得你应该去
I think you should go.
而不是埋头于工作
Instead of trying to bury yourself in your work
试着忘记大卫
and forget about David,
为什么不趁今晚去纪念他
why don't you take the night to celebrate him?
去那家餐厅  喝杯红酒
Go to that restaurant, have a glass of wine,
为大卫  为你们美好的回忆
toast David and all the wonderful memories
干一杯
you had with him.
我不知道  这好像有点...
I-- I don't know. That just seems...
我是说  他都已经不在了
I mean, he's gone.
我应该向前看  不是吗
I'm supposed to move on, right?
我是说  这样才更积极不是吗
I mean, that's... the healthy thing to do?
我说过
Well, like I've said,
悲伤的方式没有对错
there's no right or wrong way to grieve.
偶尔允许自己
Sometimes allowing yourself
沉浸在与所爱之人的回忆中
to indulge in memories of a loved one
就是最好的结束
is the best way to get closure.
我是不是该付你点钱
Should I be paying you for this or...
就当是朋友间的谈心吧
Well, let's just call this two friends talking, hmm?
有将军的行踪线索吗
Any leads on the General's whereabouts?
我们追踪了他的手机
We've located the phone.
并且正在范围内搜索他的亲友
We're looking for any friends or family within the area.
所有的交通枢纽都设置了警戒
And alerts are out at all transportation hubs
以防他出城
in case he skips town.
我刚和化工局的
I just got off the phone
安全负责人通过电话
with the head of security at the CMA.
她会把库存记录和监控录像送过来
She's handing over inventory logs and camera footage.
他能玩得这么大
He has to have accomplices
肯定还有同谋
to have pulled something like this off.
化工局的数据有出入
Found some discrepancies at the CMA.
当化工局焚毁沙林毒气罐时
So when the CMA incinerates its sarin canisters,
因为会排放气体  这必须向环保局报告
it emits gases that have to be reported to the EPA.
因此通过查看排放废物量
So, by looking at the amount of waste byproduct,
我们可以反推出
you can work backwards to figure out
一共销毁了多少沙林毒气
how much sarin gas is being destroyed.
这就是有出入的地方
And that's where the discrepancy comes in.
计算结果对不上
The math doesn't add up.
化工局所产出的废料量
The CMA isn't producing the amount of waste it should
与其声称销毁的化学武器量不符
for the amount of chemical weapons it claims to be destroying.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
将军在虚报数目吗
The general was reporting false numbers?
这样可以有效隐藏
It's one way to hide the fact
私自储藏武器的真相
that you're actually stockpiling weapons.
因此可能不止一车沙林毒气丢失了
So it might not just be a truckload of sarin that's missing.
可能远远不止
Could be a lot more.
这可是数以吨计的未烧毁原料
We're talking metric tons of material that haven't been incinerated.
有发现  将军的安保小组里有两人
We got something-- two people in a general security team
收到了来自某个神秘信托账户汇来的钱
have had their incomes padded by some mysterious trust account.
过去的这三年
For the past three years,
他们每人都得到了超过二十万美元
these guys have been paid out over 200 grand each.
给他们钱可能是那个将军
The general could have been paying them
作为他们把武器运出工厂的报酬
to transport the weapons out of the facility.
而且那个信托账户三年前还买下了
And the same trust purchased a large farm
化工局约五十公里外的一座大农场
about 30 miles outside of the CMA three years ago.
听起来是窝藏的好地方
Sounds like a good place to get off the grid.
行动吧
Let's move.
里德  伟大兄弟情终结了吗
So, Reade, is this the end of the great bromance?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你和威勒
You and Weller.
显然莎拉的事让你们有了隔阂
Well, clearly, this Sarah thing is getting in the way,
所以你们得想办法解决一下
so you guys got to sort it out.
你们让全队人都很尴尬
You're making it weird for the whole team.
昨晚我和莎拉分手了
Sarah and I broke up last night.
你犯什么错了
What'd you do?
没犯错  是我提出分手的
Nothing. I broke up with her.
你不是说为她痴狂吗
Thought you said you were crazy about her.
我真的不想谈这个了
I really don't want to talk about it.
好吧
Okay.
我觉得我们把纹身看得太简单了
I think we're looking at the tattoos too myopically.
何以见得
How so?
给简纹卡车标志的那个人
Whoever put that truck logo tattoo on Jane
对他们的秘密很了解
had very specific insider knowledge,
我们之前破解的那些纹身也是
same with every other tattoo case we've worked.
我们应该退一步
We need to take a step back
查查那些可以接触这类信息的人
and look at who might have access to this kind of information.
你的建议是什么
What are you proposing?
我们查一下已经侦破案件
We look at the connections between the players
和当事人之间的关系
and the cases we've solved.
政府机构
The government institutions,
甚至案发地点
even the locations of the crimes.
一定有线索可以指出
There must be some clue that points us
谁给简纹身  意图是什么
to who did this to Jane and why.
可现在  我的团队捉襟见肘
But right now, my entire team is stretched thin
只能调查浮出水面的那些纹身
just investigating the tattoos as they come up.
你需要人手
You need more people.
我需要很多人手
I need a lot more people.
局长在计划节约开支
The director's looking for cuts,
而不是增加开销
not added expenditures.
我明白
I understand,
但这是局里现在最重要的案子
but this is the most important case that the Bureau has.
我同意
I agree...
但每个人都觉得自己的案子最重要
but everybody feels that way about their cases.
这样吧  我想想办法
Look, I'll see what I can do.
好的
Okay.
这什么都没有
There's nothing here.
帕特森  你确定是这里吗
Patterson, you positive this is the location?
你们正在水上走呢
Um, you guys are walking on water.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在看三年前的卫星图像
I'm looking at a satellite image from three years ago,
你们站的地方过去正好是个水塘的中央
and you're standing smack in the middle of what used to be a pond.
好吧  有人把水塘抽干了
Well, someone drained the pond.
不仅如此
not only that,
供给这片土地的电力
but the electricity built for that property
高得惊人
is off the charts.
这里一定有什么被我们忽视了
Well, there is definitely something here we're missing.
散开
Fan out.
我们找找
Let's have a look.
你有没有想过
Did you think for a minute
艾玛看到你来是什么感觉
how Emma would feel about you being here?
我没做错什么  柯特
I didn't do anything wrong, Kurt.
你也许不信我
You may not believe me,
但泰勒的失踪
but I didn't have anything to do
和我没有任何关系
with Taylor's disappearance.
住口  爸爸
Stop, Dad.
我有权来这里
I have every right to be here,
就和其他人一样
just as much as anyone else
有权来悼念她
who wants to pay their respects.
你还不明白吗
You don't get it, do you?
没人愿意看到你来
No one wants you here.
没人
No one.
有发现了
Got something.
这是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
不知道
Don't know.
用这个试试
Hey, try this.
谢了
Thanks.
来吧
Come on.
打开了
There we go.
已就位
Set.
将军
General!
别开枪
Don't shoot.
C4  烈性炸药
站起来  放下武器  将军
Get on your feet and put down that weapon, General.
整个房间都装满了炸药
The entire room is rigged to blow.
解除引爆装置  将军
Disarm that detonator now, General.
别再往前走了
Don't come any closer.
-快点解除  -别再往前走了
- Disarm it! - Don't come any closer!
否则都得死
Or we all die.
这些箱子里
These crates.
装着沙林
Sarin.
美国陆军化工原料局
芥子气
Mustard gas.
氰化氢
Hydrogen cyanide.
如果我松开这个按钮
Nobody gets out alive...
没有人能活着出去
if I take my finger off this button.
你的工作是销毁这些化学武器
Your job was to destroy these chemical weapons.
我们的敌人不仅有化学武器  还有生物武器
Our enemies have chemical and biological weapons.
非裔美国黑人的传统圣歌  歌颂团结一致
你觉得我们烧掉武器储备  高唱《康巴亚》
You think that we're setting an example
是在树立榜样吗
by burning our stockpile, singing "Kumbaya"?
这是痴心妄想
It's delusional!
我们得保持武器储备
We need to maintain the stockpile.
你把武器卖给外国了吗
Did you sell it to a foreign country?
我需要资金来维持这个仓库
I needed a way to pay for this facility,
所以我卖了一点给我们的同盟  韩国
so I sold a nominal amount to South Korea, our allies.
然后有人发现了你的交易并且伏击了他们
Then someone found out about your sale and ambushed them.
因为你  成千上万条生命
Thousands of lives are at risk now...
危在旦夕
because of you.
你知道你这样做有多自私吗
Do you realize how selfish your actions are?
我从伊拉克活着回来
I lived through Iraq.
我见过无辜的生命
I saw innocent lives
被化学武器摧残
destroyed by chemical weapons,
严重残疾的孩子们
kids with horrible deformities,
整个村子被屠杀  因为萨达姆知道
entire villages wiped out because Saddam knew
他不会被抓  而我们不会反击
he could get away with it, that we wouldn't retaliate.
这一切不能再次发生
That can't happen again.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你不会引爆炸弹的
You're not going to detonate the C4.
你不想死
You don't want to die.
你做的这一切是为了拯救生命
You did all this to save lives,
而不是摧毁生命
not take them.
简
Jane...
别再往前走了
You stay back.
-瞄准他了吗  -是的
- Got him? - On him.
别动
Don't move.
是谁偷的化学武器
Who stole the chemical weapons?
是谁
Who?
韩国有一个联络人
South Koreans had a liaison.
瓦妮莎·张
Vanessa Chang
站起来
Stand up.
Stand up!
她出卖你了吗
She double-crossed you?
过去的三年里我们每季度
We've been doing deliveries of sarin to Seoul
都会向首尔运送沙林毒气
every quarter for the last three years.
只有她知道
She's the only one who knows
具体的进出口数量
the ins and the outs of the operation.
她要把武器卖给谁
Who is she selling it to?
我不知道  但当我发现是她偷的武器时
I don't know, but when I realized it was her,
我怕她会到这里来
I was afraid she'd come here.
我知道我必须在一切无法挽回之前
I knew I needed to destroy all this
毁掉这些武器
before it's too late.
丢了多少沙林毒气
How much sarin is missing?
四十罐
40 canisters.
瓦妮莎有没有帮你把武器
Did Vanessa help you move the weapons
运送到韩国
out of the country to Korea?
通过她的公司运送的
Through her company.
帕特森  查查张的发货日志
Patterson, search Chang's shipping logs.
看看今天有没有货要运出
See if she has anything leaving today.
她的公司有三个集装箱
Looks like her company has three containers
今晚要从海上运出
set to sail for tonight.
有两个要运往日本  还有
Two are headed for Japan and...
稍等
Hang on.
有一个集装箱本来要运到泰国
Looks like she had one set to sail for Thailand,
但是上周她把目的地改成了中国
but she changed the destination last week to China.
联络港务局
Contact Port Authority.
告诉他们我们马上过去
Tell 'em we're on our way.
集装箱应该就在这
Container should be in here.
这图案和萨姆的钥匙卡上的一样
Hey, it's the same logo as Sam's keycard.
干得好  塔莎
Nice work, Tasha.
联调局  不许动
FBI! Freeze!
美国陆军化工原料局
简  跟着我
Jane, with me.
收起枪  有沙林毒气  太危险
Guns away. Too risky with the sarin gas.
我的解毒剂瓶碎了
The antidote vial is broken!
来  用我的
Here, I've got mine.
不行  你怎么办
No! What about you?
坚持住  柯特
Hang on, Kurt!
她需要你的解毒剂
She needs your antidote!
我来处理她
I'm on her.
解毒剂来了
I got it, here!
你的目标是哪里  瓦妮莎
What's your target, Vanessa?
你的目标是哪里
What is your target?!
你们来晚了
You're too late.
你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
没事
Fine.
你扎我的地方很疼
I'm sore where you stabbed me.
抱歉  下次我会任由你的内脏融化
Sorry, next time I'll just let your internal organs melt.
我们检查了所有集装箱
We just checked all the containers.
一共有36罐沙林毒气
36 canisters of sarin accounted for.
将军说有40罐被偷
The General said that 40 were stolen.
不论瓦妮莎卖给了谁
Whoever Vanessa sold the sarin to
那个人拿走了四罐
took four canisters.
很可能会用于美国本土
Presumably to use on home soil.
你觉得她在协助袭击本土的目标吗
Do you think she was helping them with an American target?
你为谁效命
Who do you work for?
如果你不帮我们
Thousands of people,
成千上万的人  包括我们
including us and your own family,
以及你的家人都有可能会接触到沙林毒气
could be exposed to the sarin if you don't help us.
你为谁效命
Who do you work for?!
朝鲜
North Korea.
你们的集装箱是运往中国的
Your container was headed for China.
计划是将那些板条箱
The plan was to move the crates
经由中国运到朝鲜
through China into North Korea.
-本土目标是哪里  -我不知道
- What's the target here? - I don't know.
-我不信  -本土目标是哪里
- I don't believe you! What is the target here?
我只是向他们售卖武器
I sold them the weapons, that's it.
我完全不知道他们会在本土使用
I had no idea they were planning to use them here.
韩国付钱让我帮助将军
The South Koreans pay me to help the general.
但朝鲜出价更高
But the North Koreans made me a better offer.
背后搞鬼的是朝鲜政府吗
The North Korean government is behind this?
他们是政府中的激进派
They're a radical faction within the government.
你完全不知道他们要袭击哪里
And you have no idea what they're going to target?
我发誓  我不知道
I swear to you, I don't know.
在枪手车里找到这些
We found these in one of the shooter's cars.
吸尘器吗
Vacuum cleaners?
不完全对
Not exactly.
他们将其掏空
They hollowed out the inside
在里面放沙林毒气罐
so they could fit the sarin gas canisters.
在另一辆车里找到两罐
We recovered two canisters in another vehicle.
但有四罐下落不明
But four are missing.
还有两罐在外面
Two more are out there.
还找到了这些
They also had these.
雷普利托管业务公司
"Ripley Custodial Service."
他们会伪装成清洁工
They're gonna disguise themselves as janitors.
我们知道目标在本地
Well, we know the target's local.
问题是在哪里
The question is, where?
你查到什么
What'd you find?
我在查雷普利托管业务公司
I'm looking into Ripley Custodial Services.
雷普利托管业务公司
这间公司负责曼哈顿五幢大楼的保洁工作
This company cleans five buildings in Manhattan.
有明显的目标吗
Any obvious targets?
证券交易所
The stock exchange.
自由市场  证券交易所
今天有大型首次公开募股
Big IPO today,
奥科曼工业公开上市
Ockman Industries went public.
媒体肯定蜂拥而至
There's gonna be a lot of press there all day.
离收盘还有45分钟
45 minutes until the closing bell.
他们会在大家离开前进行毒气袭击
They'll want to hit it before everybody leaves for the day.
行动  走
Let's move, now.
已经25年了
It's been 25 years,
但感觉就像刚刚发生一样
but it's like it just happened.
他一直没放下
He never moved on.
你确定你想继续这么做吗
You sure you're still okay with this?
不能冒险去打草惊蛇
We can't risk tipping these guys off.
要同时制服他们
It needs to be a simultaneous takedown.
如果只拿下一个
If we only get one,
另一个就可能会释放毒气
we risk the other one setting off the sarin.
我们根本不知道他们在楼里的位置
We have no idea where they are in the building.
帕特森刚把楼层平面图发给我了
Patterson just sent me the floor plan.
自由市场  证券交易所
尚未发现嫌犯
No visual on the suspect yet.
路透社
里德
Reade.
我们在跟踪其中一个
We're trailing one, but we can't
在发现其同党前  不能拿下他
take him down till we've got eyes on the other.
简  在下面
Jane, down there.
我们看到第二个嫌疑人了
Okay, we got eyes on the second suspect.
他在交易大厅
He's on the trading floor.
我们的目标刚进来了
Ours just entered.
我们不在那一层
We're on the wrong floor.
来不及抓他了
We'll never get to him in time.
我能搞定
I got him!
简  你干什...
Jane, what are you--
简穿过玻璃跳下去时
Should have seen the look on your face
你被吓得不轻啊
when Jane jumped through that window.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事  我就是想下班前
Yeah, I'm just trying to finish some paperwork
写完报告
before I get outta here.
我可以等你
I can wait.
不用  没事  明天见
No, I'm cool. I'll see you tomorrow.
听着
Look...
我知道这不关我事
I know this is none of my business.
我觉得你不该跟莎拉分手
I think you're making a mistake with Sarah.
你跟她在一起很幸福
You were really happy with her.
我从没见过你这么幸福
Like, happier than I've ever seen you.
换做我  我一定会把握住这份感情
If I were you, I would hold on to that.
你真以为那么容易吗
You really think it's that easy?
你不奇怪大家为何都单身吗
You ever wonder why all of us are single?
我们选这份工作是有原因的  这是使命
We chose this job for a reason, that's who we are.
老婆孩子热炕头
We're not meant to go home
这种幸福日子不属于我们
to happy wives and husbands with kids.
对我们来说行不通
It doesn't work that way for us.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常漂亮
It's so beautiful.
不客气
It's my pleasure.
这是你妈妈的
It belonged to your mom.
她在你出生时买的
She bought it when you were born...
为了搭配你眼睛的颜色
to match your eyes.
你怎么...
How did you...
她去世后
After she passed away,
你家人变卖了一些她的旧物
some of her things were sold.
我知道这条项链对她意义非凡
I knew how much that necklace meant to her,
所以我买下了
so I bought it.
现在它是你的了
Now it's yours.
想请我喝杯东西庆生吗
Do you want to buy me a birthday drink?
我很乐意  但我今晚有事
Yeah, I'd love to, but I've got plans tonight.
艾莉
Allie.
-对  -也是
- Yeah. - Right.
改天吧
Another night.
好  当然
Yeah, okay. Of course.
-好吧  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
晚安
Night.
里德  过来一下
Reade... A moment.
坐吧
Take a seat.
我惹上麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
自从那天我们谈过以后
Something's been bugging me
我就一直感觉不对劲
ever since our chat the other day.
我很欣赏你的诚实
I appreciate you being honest
坦白自己对简有偏见  但是...
about your bias against Jane, but...
那次谈话你太反常了
Everything about that talk just feels off.
你觉得我说谎了吗
You think I'm lying?
我觉得我们品性一样
I think we're wired the same.
我还是探员时  大家就知道我直言不讳
Even as a young agent, everybody knew me as a straight shooter.
我当你这是夸我了
I'll take that a compliment.
只有一次  我背离了自己的本性
The only time I ever strayed from my instincts
因为我太害怕了
was when I was scared.
我不知道你面临的是什么
Now, I don't know what you're dealing with,
但我觉得你该告诉我
but I think you need to tell me.
我告诉过你真相了
I told you the truth.
很遗憾你不信我
I'm sorry if you don't believe me,
我不知道还能说什么
but I don't know what else to say.
还有别的事吗
Anything else?
没了
No.
五千块
Five grand.
谢谢
Thank you.
您要先点些喝的东西吗
Could I start you off with something to drink?
好
Yes.
波旁威士忌
Bourbon, please.
布兰顿系列  不加冰
Blanton's, neat.
这真是个错误
This was a mistake.
是啊  布雷特系列才适合你
I know, you're more of a Bulleit girl.
我是说来这里
Just... coming here.
我们很爱来这里
We love it here.
大卫  你都死了
David, you're dead.
都是细节而已
Details, details.
把我的填字游戏带来了吗
Did you bring my crossword puzzle?
你能在上甜点前做完吗
Think you can finish by the time dessert comes?
这是挑战吗
Is that a challenge?
先来个简单的
We'll start easy.
纵下52格  交通中枢  三个字
52 down, Midway alternative, five letters.
奥黑尔
O'Hare.
很好
Nice.
还是很厉害啊
You still got it.
里德  真的吗
Reade? Really?
我是不会让自己姐妹跟咱俩任何一个交往
I wouldn't want my sister dating one of us.
跟我俩交往总会有很多麻烦
We come with too many complications.
干杯
Cheers.
但有件事你不能再做了
The thing that does have to stop, though...
就是你总是为每一个人担心
is you always worrying about everyone
操心一切
and everything.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
今早给你送点心时
I saw that look on your face
我瞧见你的表情了
when I brought you that muffin this morning.
女友送来惊喜早餐
That was not a normal human reaction
正常人可不是这种反应啊
when the girl you like surprises you with breakfast.
我当时见到你很开心
I was genuinely happy to see you.
还有那个松饼
And the muffin.
-柯特  -怎么了
- Kurt... - What?
我们经历过一次了
We've been down this road before.
通常你会在这时候打退堂鼓
This is usually the time where you get cold feet.
我们在一起很开心
We're having fun.
都没吵过架
We haven't had a fight.
床事也欢愉
The sex is good.
退回上一句
Whoa, back it up.
什么叫"欢愉"
What do you mean... "Good"?
好吧  非常棒
Okay, great.
-干柴烈火行了吧  -行
- The sex is great. - Okay.
继续说
Keep-- keep going.
你到底想说什么
What's your point?
我的重点是
My point is...
进展顺利  我不想你毁掉这份美好
I don't want you sabotaging something because it's going great.
好吗
Okay?
现在趁泰国菜还没送来之前
Now throw me around like a rag doll
尽情与我翻云覆雨吧
before the Thai food gets here.
遵命  女王
Yes, ma'am.
我们需要你跟威勒更亲近些
We need you to get closer to Weller.
什么叫更亲近
What do you mean closer?
我们没料到
We didn't anticipate him
他会和艾莉复合
getting back together with Allie.
你想让我破坏他们的关系吗
You want me to break them up?
我们需要你成为他最信任的人
We need you to be the one person he trusts the most.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
不  他经历了太多了
No, he's-- he's been through enough, and...
我看见他在她面前的样子了  我觉得
I see the way he is around her and I think
她能给他幸福
that she's good for him.
重点不是他经历了什么
It's not about what he's been through,
重点是任务
it's about the mission.
不  我做不到
No, I can't.
不  你能做到
Yes, you can.
我们都在做出牺牲
We're all making sacrifices.
你"牺牲"了什么
What "sacrifices" are you making?
你以为这是我想要的吗
You think this is what I want?
我们曾经...
We were...
你知道我有多辛苦吗
Do you have any idea how hard it is
与你相见  却不能碰你
to meet with you and not touch you
不能对你说我爱你
and not tell you that I love you?
你以为我想让你去接近他吗
You think I want you getting closer to him?
我不知道你想要什么
I don't know what you want.
找到一个  帕特森
"找到一个  帕特森"
"Got one... Patterson."
慢着  你特地为我设定的
Wait, you put this in for me.
找到一个什么
Got one what?
你又解开了一个纹身吗
Did you solve another tattoo?